<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Scorpio Intelligence</title>
 <link href="https://scorpiointel.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://scorpiointel.github.io"/>
 <updated>2020-07-20T08:22:08+01:00</updated>
 <id>https://scorpiointel.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Scorpio Intelligence</name>
   <email>ben@scorpiointel.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>China On The Move</title>
   <link href="https://scorpiointel.github.io/china%20on%20the%20move/2020/07/17/china-on-the-move"/>
   <updated>2020-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://scorpiointel.github.io/china%20on%20the%20move/2020/07/17/china-on-the-move</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;We bring to you 5 key trends from this weeks China news report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✏️ Jessica Yu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;china-on-the-move&quot;&gt;China on the move&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cotm1/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shanghai Composite Index adjustment&quot; title=&quot;A Share Market adjustment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China’s A-share market has undergone a major adjustment with the Shanghai Composite Index falling by 5% for the entire week, the largest weekly drop in nearly five months. &lt;a href=&quot;https://capital.com/szse-component-index-definition&quot;&gt;SZSE Component Index&lt;/a&gt;, SME (Small and Medium Enterprise) board Index and GEM (growth enterprise market) Index all dropped over 4%. The transaction volume also shrank gradually and dropped to 1116.1 billion RMB on Friday, which was a substantial decrease amounting to 400 billion yuan from the previous trading day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cotm1/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SMIC IPO&quot; title=&quot;SMIC Sci-Tech&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 16, the chip manufacturing giant &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smics.com/en/&quot;&gt;SMIC&lt;/a&gt; (Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation) listed on the Sci-Tech innovation board. Its IPO price was set at 27.46 yuan, with the first day’s closing price rising 201.97% to 82.92 yuan. The company reported a turnover of 47.97 billion, which accounted for nearly 50% of the turnover of all stocks listed on the Sci-Tech innovation board, and ranked among the fourth largest single stock transaction value in the history of the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cotm1/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cambricon Technologies Corporation Limited IPO&quot; title=&quot;Cambricon Technologies Corporation Limited&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cambricon Technologies Corporation Limited will be listed on the Sci-Tech innovation board on July 20. The issue price is 64.39 yuan per share. After the issuance, the company’s market value will be 25.762 billion yuan. The number of unrestricted circulating shares at the beginning of the listing is 31,104,785 shares, accounting for 7.77% of the total share capital after this issuance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cooperation partners of the strategic placement include 4 investors: Lenovo (Beijing), Midea, OPPO and CITIC Securities. In addition, there have been many well-known institutions in the previous public offerings, such as Ali Ventures and iFLYTEK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cotm1/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;China Unicorn Enterprise TOP 100&quot; title=&quot;China Unicorn Enterprise TOP 100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the 2020 China Unicorn Enterprise TOP 100 list released by iiMedia Research, it shows that Ant Financial Services Group, ByteDance, Xiaoju Technology, Lufax, Cainiao Network Technology, Kuaishou Technology, SZ DJI Innovations, We Bank, Bitmain, and Hut information rank among the top 10. The companies are selected from unlisted and independently operating corporate enterprises with a valuation of more than 1 billion US dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of regional distribution, more than 80% of the TOP100 unicorn companies are clustered in Beijing, Shanghai, Shenzhen and Hangzhou, and the Matthew effect is becoming more and more significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cotm1/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tencent small store&quot; title=&quot;Tencent small store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tencent recently announced that the WeChat small store has officially launched. According to reports, the WeChat small store is a new capability provided by the small program team to help merchants quickly generate small programs for selling goods at zero cost. The small store provides functions such as product information release information, merchandise transactions and live broadcasts. It fully gives merchants’ independent store operation functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, WeChat’s monthly active user count is just under 1.2 billion. This is a great vertically integrated opportunity for WeChat to capitalise on their users.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
